Attila Fustos

E-mail: attila@fustos.com
Homepage: www.attila.fustos.com
Phone number: +84.10.8510.1974

Date of birth: 1978
Nationality: Hungarian
Gender: male



WORK EXPERIENCE

Samsung C&T 1/2012-

Manager, Seoul, HQ, South Korea - Civil Engineering Centre, Road and Railroad Team

Bid preparation for major infrastructure projects: 300km+ railway line, ports, mining facility Working with local partners on site by relocating to UAE, Australia and Singapore

Technical support for construction of highway and metro projects in UAE, Turkey and Korea

Gap year 10/2010-1/2012

I obtained my goal of fluency in Spanish by studying and living in Mexico and Guatemala

Mott MacDonald Group Limited

3/2008-10/2010

Chartered Bridge Engineer, London, UK - Metros & Civil Division

Design, independent check and assessment of structures in the **city of London**, **UK and UAE** Including 80m span arch road- and railbridges, jetty structure on the Thames

Quality, Environment and Safety (QES) Management System Representative

Fomterv Ltd. 7/2004–3/2008

Bridge Designer Engineer, Budapest, Hungary - Department of Bridge Engineering

Project management and site representative role on construction of for bridges, metro stations

Desing including 312 m span world record holder arch bridge construction and transportation

PROFESSIONAL STATUS

Chartered Engineer and Member of the Institution of Civil Engineers (CEng, MICE)

EDUCATION

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungary, MSC 1998–2005

Faculty of Civil Engineering, Structural engineer

Corvinus University of Budapest, Hungary, MSC 2000–2006

Faculty of Business Administration, Management and Organization

Cracow University of Technology, Poland, CEEPUS Scholarship 2001

Institute of Computer Methods in Civil Engineering, interim research project with relocation

LANGUAGE CAPABILITY

English: fluent, Spanish: competent, Hungarian: mother tongue

Attila Fustos Resume appendix September 2011

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

Over seven years' experience in the design and construction of **major civil engineering transport infrastructure**, including: bridges, underground stations, underpasses, ports, railways and highways.

Two and a half years' **experience working in the UK** on British and overseas projects with one of the biggest engineering cunsulting firm. From 2012 I am based in Seoul and support bid proposals or give technical support for major construction projects working for the company **9th on Interbrand's Best Global Brands**. Supporting different projects I moved different cities like Perth, Singapore and Abu Dhabi for at least a month period. My role is support the bidding team, consult with the client, authorities, designers and our joint venture partners.

PROFESSIONAL STATUS

Chartered Engineer and Member of the Institution of Civil Engineers (CEng, MICE)

Chartered Member of the Chamber of Hungarian Engineers

Member of the European Federation of National Engineering Associations (Eur Ing)

Member of International Association for Bridge and Structural Engineering (IABSE)

Construction Skills Certification Scheme Black Construction Site Manager Card (CSCS)

ENGINEERING SPECIALIZATIONS

Design contribution: from feasibility study to construction design, assessment and strengthening.

Structure types, construction processes: arch bridges, integral bridges, post-tensioned concrete bridge, prestressed beam - concrete composite, steel girder - concrete composite.

Carried load types: pedestrian, road, special industrial truck, rail and light rail bridges.

Special design expertises: bridge lifting and transportation, pipe-jacking, hydraulic bed bridge lifting, incremental launching girder calculation, top-down construction method for underground station construction (Milan method), bridge load test calculation, strain gauges, cable stressing process calculation, scaffolding and temporary work for bridge construction.

Engineering management: project management in structural and general construction projects, bidding and tender documentation, British quality management system for engineering process, joint ventures, design consultant management, construction contracts.

Computer skills: various engineering applications, computer programming C++ and other computer languages, MS Office with Visual Basic programming.

Codes and Standards: several local and international engineering standards and design codes

PUBLICATIONS

Nasztanovics F., Füstös A., Sapkás Á., Nagy Zs. and Horváth A.: **Sensitivity analysis of Pentele bridge, Journal article (Hungarian)**, Építés-építészettudomány, pp. 103-117, 2008, DOI: 10.1556/EpTud.36.2008.1-2.5

Horváth A., Füstös A., Nagy Zs., Nasztanovics F., Sapkás Á.: **Erection of Dunaújváros Danube Bridge**, IABSE Symposium on Responding to Tomorrow's Challenges in Structural Engineering, Budapest, 13-15 September 2006.

Nasztanovics F, Füstös A, Bojtár I: **Strength analysis of brain aneurysm**, In: I. Hungarian Conference on Biomechanics, pp. 303-313, Budapest, 11-12 Jun 2004.

Bojtár I., Nasztanovics F., Füstös A.: **FEM analysis of brain aneurysm**. IX. MaMeK, Hungarian National Conference on Mechanics, Miskolc, 27-29 August 2003.

Füstös A., Nasztanovics F.: **Analysis of dental implants under dynamic loads**. Institute of Computer Methods in Civil Engineering - Seminar, Cracow, 8 November 2001.

Bojtár I., Nasztanovics F., Füstös A., Divinyi T., Szűcs A.:: **Analysis of dental implants under dynamic loads**. 13th Inter-Institute Seminar, Vienna, 26-28 October 2001.

Füstös A., Nasztanovics F.: **Stress distribution in a plate with an elliptical hole**. 12th Inter-Institute Seminar on Nonlinear Computational Mechanics, Budapest, 27-29 October 2000.

Attila Fustos Resume appendix September 2011

DETAILED EXPERIENCE RECORD, ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Company	Project, role identity	Date	Value or main typical data	Personal responsibilities
	Quality, Environment and Safety (QES) Management System Representative, Bridge Department, Head office	12/2009-	QES for approximately 70 staff members and 50 ongoing projects	I worked with the divisional manager and acted as the focal point for the coordination of activities relating to the implementation and maintenance of the company's QES system at the local level. My role involved communicating changes to the system with advice on implications on working practices.
ment,	Support member for the new Project Information Manage- ment System (PiMS)	12/2008-	Assistant of approximately 10 staff members	Delivering the introduction of a new management system to the department which involved the reorganisation of the information processes
ld Ltd. idge Depart Engineer 10/2010	Pudding Mill Lane, Crossrail, new underground line, London	9/2009-	A 19m span single supported bridge and a 19m span integral bridge constructed for Crossrail during the Olympics in London in the city centre for heavy and DLR (Docklands Light Railway) rail lines	Designer of the bridges according to British and DLR standards , in accordance to the Crossrail project terms and conditions .
ra ,nois Bridge	Margit Bridge refurbishment, Budapest, Hungary	2-3/2009	Bidding for the historical bridge reconstruction in Hungary	I contributed towards the preparation of the bid document
partered	Accommodation Bridges, M4 Highway, UK	2-4/2009	Series of 36m span post-tensioned concrete accommoda- tion bridges, constructed in 1970	Bridge assessment calculation and possible deterioration analysis. Assessment report preparation according to the British Highway Agency design manual (BD)
1)	Boulevard Bridges, Al Raha Development, United Arab Emir- ates (UAE)	8/2008-	12 pieces of independent 80m long span network arch bridges which comprised different decks: 3-5 lanes carriageways or light railway line above a channel	Independent design check with the application of the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials (AASHTO)
V	Belvedere Access Bridge, on the bank of the Thames, London, UK	5-8/2008	7 span, 115m continuous prestressed beam concrete composite bridge structure in maritime area, carrying industrial truck traffic	Designer of the bridge according to the British Standard (BS).
	Ryde Pier, Isle of Wight, UK	3-5/2008	120m multi-span concrete approach bridge, carrying pedestrian and railway traffic, substructure constructed in the early 19th century	Structure assessment and strengthening report according to BS, as a member of the team.
Bridge er	Fovam underpass, Budapest, Hungary	9/2007-	8.2 million GBP, whole junction reconstruction connecting different level perpendicular tram lines. The underpass is right next to historic river bridge abutment carrying the main water supply for Budapest	General project manager assistant and structural designer. I assisted the general design project manager during the reconstruction process. The whole refurbishment included the site supervision and consultation with the stakeholders
terv Ltd. artment, DV2004-3	Bocskai underground station, Metro 4 new underground line (M4), Budapest, Hungary	1-9/2007	18m deep, 20m wide and 130m long box underground structure, construction type: top-down (Milan) method, situated between high buildings.	Designer of the station and design assistant manager Site representative on behalf of the designer
dəD e	Tetenyi underground station, M4, Budapest, Hungary	9/2007	Half-cone shaped light weight steel roof structure	I carried out a feasibility design for the structure
]	Dunakeszi railway bridge	10/2007	26m length, single span, steel-girder concrete topping composite bridge over a railway line	Assessment and strengthening documentation of the bridge
1	Szolnok footbridge	8-9/2007	200m span length pedestrian river bridge	Feasibility study working together with the architects

Attila Fustos Resume appendix September 2011

Company	Project, role identity	Date	Value or main typical data	Personal responsibilities
mterv Ltd. e Department, 1, 7/2004-3/2008	Pentele river bridge on the Dan- ube at Dunaújváros, Hungary	8/2004-7/2007	132 million GBP, main span: 312m, 50m height, 43m width, 86.00 tons total length: 1682m lts main span is world record holder in its type: it is the longest spanning Nielsen-Lohse type arch bridge in the world. The transportation (erection) of the main span was a unique engineering task in this scale. The approach bridge is a continuous multi-span lunched box-girder.	I worked on the design of the bridge from the beginning of the design till the opening procedure. Detailed design of the transportation process, the floating procedure dure of the main span Load test of the barges for the transportation process with strain gauges Detailed mechanical analysis and optimization of different parts of the structure independent check of the cable stressing process Steel assembly and construction modelling with pioneer full 3D steel assembly and construction modelling with pioneer full 3D steel structure modelling process Project manager of the calculation team for the load test procedure (strain gauges and simultaneous survey)
вр <u>і</u> Эв	M7 highway bridges	3/2006	3 bridges 40m span, highway bridges	Assessment of bridges
Brid	Duna Tower underpass	7-9/2006	20m length, trapeze section of 4m height, 6m width, pipe- jacked underpass with prefabricated structural elements	Conceptual design of the tunnel
	Esztergom-Sturovo River Bridge connecting the Hungarian- Slovakian sides	9/2006	Main span: 250m, 3D modelling, layouts for design competi- tion, green field conception design	Feasibility design of a country border bridge, team member
,	Szolnok-Mezotur railway un- derpass	3-5/2005	Underpass bridge for a railway station, span 12m depth 6m, European Union project	Implementation design of the underpass tunnel
	M7 highway bridge	7-9/2004	40m span, precast beam in-situ filled concrete deck accommodation bridge	Design and CAD detailing of the bridge
Gedeon Richter Plc.	Summer placement, Cadet engineer	7-8/2003	Factory refurbishment projects, 4 small projects, sum 50000 GBP	Cost estimate, tender calculation, project management contractor site representative
Stusoft YasgauH Lid	Mesh generation programming	7-10/2002	Special mesh algorithm using C++ for a Finite Element (FEM) program	Programming a special procedure for the software
J	Strength analysis of brain aneurysm	9/2002- 10/2004	Coupled (mechanical-flow) 3D FEM analysis	Research team member
nical sity o	CEEPUS Scholarship, Cracow, Poland	10-11/2001	Research study at the Institute of Computer Methods in Civil Engineering Department	Research team member
ıəvin	Analysis of dental implants	9/2000- 9/2002	Material and support condition nonlinearity, 3D analysis	Research team member
n	Stress distribution around an elliptical hole	10/1999-	Comparing the analytical, FEM, Distinct Element Method solutions	Research team member